Speaker 1: ÔWelcome to Denver Airport. How can I help you today?Ő
Speaker 2: I handed my passport and flight confirmation to the woman at United Airlines check-in.
I was on my way to Costa Rica at the beginning of the trip of a lifetime, travelling around Central America.
The woman checked in my backpack and handed me my boarding pass.
ÔLucky you, going to California,Ő she smiled.
ÔYour gate is 37C.Ő
ÔNo. I booked a ticket to San JosŽ.Ő
ÔYes, dear. Your ticket is for San JosŽ, in California.Ő
I was horrified!
ÔIŐm so sorry, but I need your help. My ticket is for the wrong San JosŽ.Ő
This time she didnŐt smile. She pointed to the help desk for United Airlines.
The next few hours were terrible. The help desk assistant wasnŐt helpful.
ÔIŐm sorry. We canŐt change your ticket.Ő
I tried to call my travel agent, hoping they could solve the problem. No luck.
A message arrived on my phone from my dad.
It was a link to the Dionne Warwick song ÔDo you know the way to San JosŽ?Ő Not funny, Dad.
Then a new assistant arrived. ÔWhatŐs the problem?Ő she asked. I explained the situation.
ÔOf course we can book a new flight for you, dear.Ő I hugged her.
She immediately booked me onto a cheap flight to San JosŽ, Costa Rica.
Suddenly, I remembered my backpack. But it was too late.
ÔDid you check in my luggage?Ő I asked.
ÔNo. Unfortunately, itŐs on the way to California.Ő
So, after 72 hours, four flights, and three days without luggage, I can say that I know the (long) way to San JosŽ.
And I have one important lesson for you: always take spare underwear in your carry-on luggage.
And if you can fit extra jeans, a T-shirt and a sweater in there too, DO THAT!